activistpost.com 2019-12-17

# Privacy Policy - Activist Post

Users may visit our Site anonymously. We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us (such as an email address when subscribing to our mailing list). Users can always refuse to supply personally identification information. Activistpost.com uses a hit service that shows information such as which internet service visitors are using, their screen resolutions, browser types, etc… but in no way does this reveal the name, email address, or any specific information whatsoever about the site’s visitors.

### Cookies & 3rd Party Advertisements:

Our Site may use “cookies” to enhance User experience. User’s web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. User may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy. Activistpost.com is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com.

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit 

[youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) (EU users)

### Will Activistpost.com disclose collected information to outside parties?

Activistpost.com may eventually disclose the aforementioned GENERAL information about visitors – information that does NOT identify who you are. We may disclose answers to questions such as: during what time periods do we receive the most visitors, what is the most common browser version of our visitors, what are the most popular internet services our visitors use, etc. We will never release contact details of any registered users of our website. The last thing we want is “spam” reaching our visitors.

### Your Consent:

By using our Web site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by Activistpost.com. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. But, now and forever we put your privacy first before any other concerns. We will never sell lists of email addresses from this site. We respect the privacy of our visitors.

### Affiliate Disclosure:

Activistpost.com is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com.

### Newsletter:

Visitors on this site may optionally sign up for our daily newsletter by providing their email address in one of the various signup forms available on Activistpost.com. The email addresses are stored with mailchimp.com, and the user data is never shared nor sold to any outside parties. The Mailchimp privacy policy an be seen here <https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>. We use the subscribers email address to send out a daily newsletter with the most recent articles, and to communicate with regarding changes or updates on the site. In addition we also send out occasional promotional emails to our subscribers, for products that we think would be of interest. Users emails are kept safe by Mailchimp, for as long as the user remains a subscriber. Users can unsubscribe from our email list at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the base of the email.

### California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require any person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting Personally Identifiable Information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals or companies with whom it is being shared. – See more at: <http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/>

**According to CalOPPA, we agree to the following:**  
Users can visit our site anonymously.  
Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum, on the first significant page after entering our website.  
Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can easily be found on the page specified above.  
You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes on our Privacy Policy Page.  
Can change your personal information by emailing us or via an online form.

**How does our site handle Do Not Track signals?**  
We honor Do Not Track signals and Do Not Track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?**  
It’s also important to note that we allow third-party behavioral tracking

### COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, United States’ consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under the age of 13 years old.

### Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:  
We will notify you via email within 7 business days.  
We will notify the users via in-site notification within 7 business days.

We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle which requires that individuals have the right to legally pursue enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

### CAN SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

**We collect your email address in order to:**  
• Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred.

**To be in accordance with CANSPAM, we agree to the following:**  
• Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.  
• Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.  
• Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.  
• Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.  
• Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.  
• Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can follow the instructions at the bottom of each email and we will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence.

User Access Request  
Users have well-defined rights when it comes to having access to their personal data. When you submit a user request using our contact form or by sending us a request to the address provided below, we will provide the following information free of charge:

What personal information pertaining to the user is being processed  
Why this information is being processed  
Who has access to this personal information about the user  
How this personal information is being used in automated decisions  
What processes are using this information  
Your user access request will be completed within 30 days and will include a copy of what personal information we have on file.

### Contacting Us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us using the information below.

Activist Post S.A.  
APDO 376-4013  
Atenas Centro, Alajuela  
20501 Costa Rica

Last updated on May 31, 2018
